Even robbers get robbed.
Play Dirty is a crime film directed by Shane Black.
Expert thief Parker gets a shot at a major heist, but to pull it off he and his team must
outsmart a South American dictator, the New York mob, and the world's richest man.
Parker, played by Mark Wahlberg.
Grofield, played by LaKeith Stanfield.
Zen, played by Rosa Salazar.
Ed Mackey, played by Keegan-Michael Key.
Phineas Paul, played by Chukwudi Iwuji.
Kincaid, played by Nat Wolff.
Play Dirty is a 2025 American heist action thriller film
co-written and directed by Shane Black.
It is based on the Parker book series by Donald E.
Westlake, written under the pen name Richard Stark.
The film stars Mark Wahlberg as the lead character Parker and LaKeith Stanfield as Grofield, another recurring Stark character,
along with Rosa Salazar, Keegan-Michael Key, Chukwudi Iwuji, Nat Wolff, Gretchen Mol, Thomas Jane, and Tony Shalhoub.
It was released by Amazon MGM Studios via Prime Video on October 1, 2025.
The film explores themes of heist, thief, insecure, reflective, wonder.